Mauricio Arango Isaza Ph.D.

marangoisa@gmail.com www.mauricio-arango.com Latest version is available here



Formal Education

- Ph.D. Economics, University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign
- M.A. Economics, Universidad del Rosario
- B.A. Degree in Economics, Universidad EAFIT

Summary of Experience

Dr. Arango has extensive experience in the use of quantitative analysis and economic theory applied to both microeconomic and macroeconomic questions. His recent work centers on applying economic and financial analyses to questions arising in complex business litigation in a diverse portfolio of industries, including automotive, steel, oil, and finance, among others.

During his doctoral studies, Dr. Arango's research focused on urban economics, real estate economics, and transportation economics. Earlier in his career, he analyzed the macroeconomic outlook of Latin American countries, with a special focus on the impact of monetary and fiscal policy. Dr. Arango has taught multiple courses in economics, both in English (University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign) and Spanish (Universidad del Rosario).

Experience

- Associate, Analysis Group. August 2022-Present
- Instructor, <u>University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign</u>, International Economics (econ420). August 2018 May 2022
- Teaching Assistant, <u>University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign</u>, Economics Statistics II (econ203). August 2016 to May 2018
- Senior Economist, Latin American Reserve Fund (FLAR). July 2013 to July 2015
- Junior Economist, Latin American Reserve Fund (FLAR). July 2011 to July 2013
- Lecturer, Universidad del Rosario, macroeconomics. February 2011 to July 2015
- Research Assistant, Universidad del Rosario. July 2009 to July 2011
- Intern, Central Bank of Colombia, Research Department. July 2008 to July 2009

Research

- Parking's Irritating Externality: The Congestion Cost of Cruising
- <u>Crowning the Metropolis: Cityscapes, Land Values, and Population</u> (with David Albouy and Minchul Shin)
- Assessing Walkability Through Parking Prices

Software

- R (advanced)
- Python (advanced)
- LaTex (advanced)
- STATA (medium)
- MATLAB (medium)
- SQL (basic)
- HTML (basic)
- ArcGIS (basic)

Journal Referee Experience

- Journal of Urban Economics
- Real Estate Economics
- Regional Science and Urban Economic

Fellowships, Awards, and Distinctions

- Travel Grant University of Illinois Economics 2019, 2020
- Summer Fellowship University of Illinois Economics 2018
- Undergraduate meritorious thesis *Universidad EAFIT* 2009

Participation in Events

- 15th North American Meeting of the Urban Economics Association, 2021
- LACEA LAMES Annual Meeting, 2021
- 10th European Meeting of the Urban Economics Association (UEA), 2021
- Virtual Meeting Midwest Economics Association (MEA), 2021
- Virtual Meeting of the Urban Economics Association (UEA), 2020
- North American Meetings of the Regional Science Council International (NARSC), 2020
- 14th North American Meeting of the Urban Economics Association (UEA), 2019
- International Transport Economics Association (ITEA) Annual Conference, 2019
- 10th Meeting of Monetary Policy Advisors. CEMLA Central Bank of Paraguay. June 19 to 20, 2014
- 23rd Annual Conference Central Bank of Uruguay, 2013
- 7th Annual Conference Central Bank of Colombia (Ensayos Sobre Política Económica, ESPE), 2011

Languages

• English (fluent), Spanish (native)

GitHub Repositories

- WebScrapingForAll (Python)
- CensuPopulationByCounty1900-2010 (R)
- RegressionVisuals (R)

Working Papers and Other Publications

- A General Equilibrium Analysis of Bank Debit Taxes
- Collateralized Assets Prices and Monetary Policy. Revista de Economía del Rosario
- El sistema crediticio, la política monetaria y un posible origen de ciclos y crisis financieras. Ensayos Sobre Política Económica (ESPE), with Carlos Esteban Posada and Jorge Andrés Tamayo
- Una caja de herramientas para incluir la política fiscal en los modelos de DSGE. ECOS de Economía